<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assignment on My messy collection</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/assignment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Assignment on My messy collection</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>cn</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 16:03:22 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/assignment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tecknoworks-Intenship challange</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/tecknoworks_challange/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 16:03:22 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/tecknoworks_challange/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;premise&#34;&gt;Premise&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This technical project is designed to evaluate your technical skills, creativity, and problem-solving abilities&#xA;in both Data Engineering and Artificial Intelligence. The project will help us assess how well you&#xA;understand the concepts and tools you&amp;rsquo;ll be working with during the internship. The project should take&#xA;no more than 2 to 3 hours to complete.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project Description&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You are tasked with designing a simple data pipeline using Microsoft Fabric and performing data science&#xA;tasks using Python. Most likely, you don&amp;rsquo;t have experience with Microsoft Fabric. We&amp;rsquo;re interested in how&#xA;your mind works when you have to face a challenge like this. Microsoft Fabric is a comprehensive data&#xA;analytics platform that integrates data engineering, data science, data warehousing, and business&#xA;intelligence in one environment. By using Microsoft Fabric, we expect our interns to gain hands-on&#xA;experience with a tool that Microsoft expects to be widely adopted in the industry. This exposure not only&#xA;makes you more competitive in the job market but also prepares you for real-world scenarios where you&#xA;are likely to encounter similar integrated platforms.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Microsoft Fabric is a paid tool, so in order to solve these exercises, you have to simply read the&#xA;documentation to have an introduction to the tool, watch a few tutorials if needed and answer the&#xA;questions based on your findings and your prior knowledge from University courses. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to&#xA;access Fabric for this basic assignment. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to implement the solution, only to design it based&#xA;on the documentation that you read. You can use text descriptions or any type of visual representation to&#xA;answer the questions (e.g. Dataflow diagrams) for Section 1. For Section 2 you can implement the solution&#xA;for free using Google Colab or any other local python environment.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The project is divided into two main sections: Data Engineering and Artificial Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
